AHMED ERAKY

ahmederaky.github.io/Eraky-Portfolio/

(+20) 111 663 0078 ahmedmoeraky@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ah-eraky

OBJECTIVE

As a Software Engineer with work experience in Fin-Tech domain (Online Payment, Smart Wallet) and E-Commerce applications, I am looking forward to using my problem solving and coding skills to build high quality software applying engineering concepts and best practices.

EMPLOYMENT

Java Software Engineer

Orange Labs, Egypt

DEC 2019 – PRESENT

Human Resources Management Solution (Spring Boot "hexagonal architecture")

- Apply Caching on Application level and Database level to improve performance.
- · Work with an agile team to develop software solution for Human Resources management.
- Support in System Design to be configurable for multiple clients with hexagonal architecture.

E-Commerce Application (Angular)

- Work with an agile team as a full stack engineer to develop an e-commerce app for selling products in UAE.
- Designed frontend architecture to optimize loading time.
- improve state management by applying Flux Pattern.

Software Engineer

Fawry Banking & Payment Services

Jul 2019 - DEC 2019

DIB Wallet

- Applying payment protocols and secure payment transactions with CyberSource.
- Designed, implemented, and consumed RESTful and SOAP APIs. Secured endpoints with OAuth2 Protocol.
- Refactor legacy code to improve maintenance.
- Build a CI/CD pipeline to automate testing and deployment processes.

Android Developer Freelancer

Self-Employed

2017 - 2018

E-Commerce Mobile Applications

- · Taking requirements from customer to build android application with Firebase Realtime database
- App: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.vegeta.my.dealer

EDUCATION

9 Months Diploma

Information Technology Institute(ITI)

OCT 2018 – JUN 2019

A practical diploma for building enterprise and web application using Java (Spring Framework)

Course work http://www.iti.gov.eg/Admission/PTPprogram/intake39/EADStrack

Selected Projects:

- Ecommerce Application: Leading a team of 5, we built a website with Java Servlet API and JSP. Demo: https://nameless-inlet-60892.herokuapp.com/
- Chat Application: Leading a team of 5, we built a desktop application using JavaFX and RMI.

Bachelor of Computer Science

Ain Shams University

SEP 2014 – MAY 2018

Graduation project: Intrusion Detection System

University Activities & Volunteering

 ACM ASCIS Student Chapter: (2016-2017) worked in the HR team, to improve the educational process for competitive programming

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Java; JavaScript; C; C++; HTML; CSS;
- Spring framework; Web Services(Rest, SOAP);
- OOP; Design Patterns;
- · Microservices; MVC; MVP; Flux;
- Algorithms; Data Structures; Problem solving

- Angular; Android;
- SQL; JPA/Hibernate; Firebase;
- · Maven; Git;
- · Docker; Jenkins;
- Agile; TDD;

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND AWARDS

Android Developer, Intern at SMartPan (AUG 2018 – SAP 2018)

Learn about android design patterns and working environment.

Google Developer Nanodegree Scholarship (SEP 2017 - MAR 2018)

A fully funded scholarship. Certificate: https://graduation.udacity.com/confirm/WNNCVHEA